<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data and Code Management :: Data and Code Management: From Collection to Application</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/index.html</link>
    <description>This website provides the support for the class Data and Code Management: From Collection to Application given at the Faculty of Business and Economics (HEC Lausanne) of the University of Lausanne in Fall (currently 2025)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/index.html</guid>
      <description>Explore the nature of this course and understand its various prerequisites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lectures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/lectures/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/lectures/index.html</guid>
      <description>Every Thursday from 9:00 to 12:00.&#xA;The ideal schedule is given below. It is subject to modifications.&#xA;Class-related discussion and questions will be on Slack. Do not forget to register here.&#xA;Warning Exceptionnally the Practical on week 6 will be on Friday 24 Oct.&#xA;Week Date Focus Session (3h) Homework 1 18 Sep 2025 Kick-off No class (Thesis &amp; Career workshops) – 2 25 Sep 2025 Introduction &amp; Tools (Lecture) - Course overview, expectations - Reproducibility in analytics - Tools: R, Python, SQL, GitHub, Markdown/Jupyter – 3 02 Oct 2025 Programming Foundations (Lecture) - Data structures (R &amp; Python)- Control structures &amp; functions- Good coding practices HW1 released (Programming foundations in R/Python) 4 09 Oct 2025 Practical 1 - R/Python coding drills (functions, loops, vectorization)- Git workflow practice HW1 discussed 5 16 Oct 2025 Data Management &amp; Collection (Lecture) - Relational databases &amp; SQL basics (SELECT, JOIN, GROUP BY)- Accessing SQL from R/Python- Web scraping (Rvest, BeautifulSoup)- APIs &amp; JSON- Storage formats &amp; best practices HW1 due HW2 released (SQL + scraping/API integration) 6 24 Oct 2025 Practical 2 - SQL queries + API/scraping mini-lab- Integrate results into R/Python HW2 discussed 7 30 Oct 2025 Software Engineering for Data Science (Lecture) - Object-oriented programming (R S3/S4, Python classes)- Functional programming- Package development- Testing &amp; documentation HW2 due HW3 released (functions, package basics, testing) 8 06 Nov 2025 Practical 3 - Functions &amp; package skeleton in R/Python- Documentation &amp; testing basics HW3 discussed 9 13 Nov 2025 Modern Tools: BI &amp; LLMs (Lecture) - Power BI for visualization &amp; storytelling- Prompt engineering for LLMs- Using LLMs for code/documentation/tests- AI copilots for analytics HW3 due 10 20 Nov 2025 Practical 4 - LLM lab: generate SQL queries, R/Python snippets- Build BI dashboard (Power BI/Shiny/Streamlit) – 11 27 Nov 2025 Project Work I - Group project supervision- Focus on reproducibility, integration, and communication – 12 04 Dec 2025 Project Work II - Group sprint: project review- Hands-on project development – 13 11 Dec 2025 Project Work III - Project refinement- Preparing final deliverables – 14 18 Dec 2025 Project Presentations - Final presentations –</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tutorials/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/tutorials/index.html</guid>
      <description>Warning These tutorials are not updated. Last update, September 2024.&#xA;This section contains the tutorials on various topics, namely, coding style guide, basics of syntax, best practice, conventions, typical workflows, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additional Exercises</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/exercises/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/exercises/index.html</guid>
      <description>Train yourself with additional exercises and their corrections.&#xA;Attachments series/serie1.pdf (121 KB)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/resources/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/resources/index.html</guid>
      <description>This page collects useful resources to support your learning in Data and Code Management: From Collection to Application.&#xA;All resources are freely available online.&#xA;Getting started with R and RStudio The CRAN website — official source for R and its documentation. An Introduction to R — official tutorial covering basics of R programming and statistical analysis. RStudio IDE — the most widely used IDE for R. RStudio cheat sheets — concise guides for R packages and workflows. The tidyverse — collection of R packages for data manipulation, visualization, and analysis. Getting started with Python Python official documentation — language reference and tutorials. Python Data Science Handbook by Jake VanderPlas — free online guide to NumPy, pandas, matplotlib, scikit-learn. Real Python — tutorials and best practices for Python programming. Pandas documentation — data wrangling in Python. Matplotlib gallery — quick examples for Python plotting. SQL and Databases Mode SQL Tutorial — interactive beginner-to-advanced SQL lessons. SQLBolt — hands-on SQL exercises. PostgreSQL documentation — reference for one of the most popular open-source databases. SQLite documentation — lightweight relational database, easy to set up. Reproducibility and Collaboration Happy Git and GitHub for the useR by Jenny Bryan — beginner-friendly guide to version control. Pro Git Book — complete reference on Git. RMarkdown and Jupyter Notebooks — tools for literate programming. Quarto — next-generation publishing system for R, Python, and Julia. Business Intelligence &amp; Visualization Power BI Documentation — tutorials and user guides from Microsoft. Mastering Shiny by Hadley Wickham — developing interactive web apps in R. Streamlit documentation — build web apps in Python for data science. ggplot2 book by Hadley Wickham — R visualization. Seaborn documentation — Python data visualization. Large Language Models (LLMs) and AI Tools Prompt Engineering Guide — strategies for effective LLM use. LangChain documentation — framework for building applications powered by LLMs in Python. OpenAI API documentation — reference for integrating LLMs into data workflows. Recommended Books Advanced R by Hadley Wickham. R for Data Science by Grolemund &amp; Wickham. Fluent Python (2nd Edition) by Luciano Ramalho. Effective Python by Brett Slatkin. SQL for Data Scientists by Renee M. P. Teate. Miscellaneous Shiny — open-source R package for interactive apps. Streamlit — Python alternative for quick dashboards. Rcpp for Seamless R and C++ Integration — extend R with C++. Engineering Production-Grade Shiny Apps — best practices for robust Shiny development.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>