<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data and Code Management :: Data and Code Management: From Collection to Application</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/index.html</link>
    <description>This website provides the support for the class Data and Code Management: From Collection to Application given at the Faculty of Business and Economics (HEC Lausanne) of the University of Lausanne in Fall (currently 2025)</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/index.html</guid>
      <description>Explore the nature of this course and understand its various prerequisites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lectures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/lectures/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/lectures/index.html</guid>
      <description>Lectures Every Thursday from 9:00 to 12:00.&#xA;The ideal schedule is given below. It is subject to modifications.&#xA;Class-related discussion and questions will be on Slack. Do not forget to register here.&#xA;Warning The lecture of the 31st of October was on Zoom. The record is on this link, passcode: 8a=3P!BE.&#xA;Week Date Topic Instructor 1 19 Sept No class (Thesis planning &amp; Career planning workshops) 2 26 Sept Introduction, RMarkdown, Github, Project Samuel 3 3 Oct Data structures, Control structures, Function Samuel 4 10 Oct Exercise and Homework 1 Timofei 5 17 Oct Object-oriented programming, Webscraping, Shiny App Samuel 6 24 Oct Exercise and Homework 2 Timofei 7 31 Oct Functional programming, Package creation, Advanced shiny App, Samuel 8 7 Nov Exercise and Homework 3 Timofei 9 14 Nov Data science with R on Google Cloud Samuel 9 21 Nov Power BI, final class Samuel 11 28 Nov Group Project Timofei 12 5 Dec Group project Timofei 13 12 Dec Group project Timofei 14 19 Dec Project Presentations Samuel and Timofei</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tutorials/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:17:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/tutorials/index.html</guid>
      <description>Tutorials This section contains the tutorials on various topics, namely, coding style guide, basics of syntax, best practice, conventions, typical workflows, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exercises</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/exercises/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/exercises/index.html</guid>
      <description>Exercises Train yourself with material presented during class.&#xA;Exercises _index.files/Exercise1_solution.pdf (141 KB) _index.files/Exercise1.pdf (123 KB) _index.files/Exercise2_solution.pdf (185 KB) _index.files/Exercise2.pdf (55 KB) _index.files/Exercise3_solution.pdf (187 KB) _index.files/Exercise3.pdf (58 KB) _index.files/Financial Sample.xlsx (81 KB) _index.files/snipes.csv (1020 B)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homeworks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/homeworks/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/homeworks/index.html</guid>
      <description>Homeworks There are four graded homeworks to be submitted at different deadlines during the semester. The homeworks represent 50% of the final grade. Time management is important for succeeding in this class, try to avoid the following example:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/project/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/project/index.html</guid>
      <description>Project Project represents 30 points, so 50% of the final grade.&#xA;Groups are here. Different requirements are explained in these slides and the pdf below.&#xA;Related files _index.files/project_summary.pdf (61 KB)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/group/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/group/index.html</guid>
      <description>Discover with whom you’re going to work with&#xA;Below are the groups. The number for the group has no meaning. The order within the group has no meaning.&#xA;Group 1 Group 2 Group 3 Group 4 Group 5 Group 6 Group 7 Fanny Iff Léo Wenger Alicia Gamal Ronald Medvedev Salvatore D’Amato Nathanaël Dürst Lodrik Adam Ambre Ferrari Urs Huerni Streuli Marvin Julien Keller Reisa Reci Hassan El Kira Jeff Macaraeg Elwin Freudiger Hugo Troendel Mariel Gandarillas Calderon Antoine Magnin Lina Dernaika Luca Marini Julien Perini Arnaud Aquin-Demierre Anastasia Pushkarev Marcela Choque Quispe Robin Michel Andrea Danesi Steve Marcello Emma Antille Olivier Dinh Valeriia Bilousko Sofia Daza Arandia Faber Bickerstaffe Thomas Bonnet Yanis Bougherara Herald Nakpil Maria Fernanda Cladera Melgar</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/resources/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 17:27:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/resources/index.html</guid>
      <description>Resources Getting started with R and Rstudio The CRAN website CRAN is a network of ftp and web servers around the world that store identical, up-to-date, versions of R and its documentation.&#xA;An Introduction to R This official and up-to-date tutorial, gives an introduction to the language and how to use R for doing statistical analysis and graphics.&#xA;RStudio RStudio is an integrated development environment (IDE) for R. It includes a console, syntax-highlighting editor that supports direct code execution, as well as tools for plotting, history, debugging and workspace management.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>