<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Syllabus :: Data and Code Management: From Collection to Application</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/index.html</link>
    <description>Explore the nature of this course and understand its various prerequisites.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>General information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/general/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/general/index.html</guid>
      <description>Location and Time Location: Anthropole/3032 Time: 9 - 12 (see the lectures schedule for more details) Course Websites Course website: https://dcm.samorso.ch/ Online textbook: https://smac-group.github.io/ds/ Discussion Forum: on slack Course Staff Instructor Name: Samuel Orso Email: Samuel.Orso@unil.ch Office: Anthropole/3090.1 Office Hours: Appointment may be made upon request. find me on GitHub Teaching Assistant Name: Timofei Shashkov Email: timofei.shashkov@unil.ch Office: Extranef/134 Office Hours: Appointment may be made upon request.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Course description</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/coursedescr/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/coursedescr/index.html</guid>
      <description>This course introduces students to the essential tools and practices of modern data and code management, with a focus on business analytics applications.&#xA;It covers a broad spectrum of programming languages and platforms — including R, Python, SQL, GitHub, Power BI, and modern AI assistants (LLMs) — to help students design reproducible, collaborative, and impactful data workflows.&#xA;Topics covered include: Reproducible research: Literate programming with RMarkdown and Jupyter Notebooks. Version control &amp; collaboration: Best practices with GitHub. Programming foundations: Data structures, logical operators, control structures, and functions in R and Python. Databases &amp; SQL: Querying, joining, and aggregating data, with integration into R and Python. Visualization &amp; reporting: From exploratory analysis with ggplot2 and Python’s visualization libraries to interactive dashboards in Power BI. Software engineering for data science: Functions, testing, documentation, and package creation in R/Python. Web &amp; data collection: Web scraping and APIs (using Rvest, BeautifulSoup, requests, etc.). Interactive applications: Development of web apps with Shiny and Streamlit. Large Language Models (LLMs): Leveraging AI assistants responsibly for code generation, documentation, and analytics. Communication &amp; dissemination: Building reproducible websites, dashboards, and reports for sharing results. Learning outcomes By the end of the course, students will be able to:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/grading/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/grading/index.html</guid>
      <description>Learning outcomes for this course are assessed continuously through homework assignments and a semester-long group project.&#xA;There is no final exam. Instead, evaluation reflects your ability to apply the course material in practice and to collaborate effectively.&#xA;Grading Breakdown Type Weight Homeworks (3 × 20%) 60% Group project 40% Participation &amp; engagement Bonus Homeworks (60%) There will be three homework assignments (20% each), aligned with the major course blocks:&#xA;HW1 (Weeks 3–5): Programming foundations in R and Python. HW2 (Weeks 5–7): SQL queries, web scraping, and API integration. HW3 (Weeks 7–9): Software engineering for data science (functions, packages, testing, documentation). Each homework is:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Communication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/communication/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/communication/index.html</guid>
      <description>Slack We will utilize Slack for discussing class-related matters and addressing inquiries. This platform is designed to facilitate collaborative learning, leveraging the combined wisdom of your peers and instructors. Please feel free to share questions with the entire class, especially if they pertain to course content. We strongly encourage you to seek clarification if you encounter difficulties grasping a concept and to offer assistance to your fellow classmates whenever possible by responding to their queries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/material/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/material/index.html</guid>
      <description>Laptops Please bring a laptop to class if possible. We encourage collaborative work, and ideally we aim for at least one laptop for every two students. Both homework assignments and the group project involve coding and teamwork, so having access to a laptop will make your learning experience smoother.&#xA;If you are considering purchasing a laptop, students from Swiss universities can benefit from preferential pricing through the Neptun Projekt or EPFL’s Poseidon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convinced?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/final/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/syllabus/final/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>