<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources :: Data and Code Management: From Collection to Application</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/resources/index.html</link>
    <description>This page collects useful resources to support your learning in Data and Code Management: From Collection to Application.&#xA;All resources are freely available online.&#xA;Getting started with R and RStudio The CRAN website — official source for R and its documentation. An Introduction to R — official tutorial covering basics of R programming and statistical analysis. RStudio IDE — the most widely used IDE for R. RStudio cheat sheets — concise guides for R packages and workflows. The tidyverse — collection of R packages for data manipulation, visualization, and analysis. Getting started with Python Python official documentation — language reference and tutorials. Python Data Science Handbook by Jake VanderPlas — free online guide to NumPy, pandas, matplotlib, scikit-learn. Real Python — tutorials and best practices for Python programming. Pandas documentation — data wrangling in Python. Matplotlib gallery — quick examples for Python plotting. SQL and Databases Mode SQL Tutorial — interactive beginner-to-advanced SQL lessons. SQLBolt — hands-on SQL exercises. PostgreSQL documentation — reference for one of the most popular open-source databases. SQLite documentation — lightweight relational database, easy to set up. Reproducibility and Collaboration Happy Git and GitHub for the useR by Jenny Bryan — beginner-friendly guide to version control. Pro Git Book — complete reference on Git. RMarkdown and Jupyter Notebooks — tools for literate programming. Quarto — next-generation publishing system for R, Python, and Julia. Business Intelligence &amp; Visualization Power BI Documentation — tutorials and user guides from Microsoft. Mastering Shiny by Hadley Wickham — developing interactive web apps in R. Streamlit documentation — build web apps in Python for data science. ggplot2 book by Hadley Wickham — R visualization. Seaborn documentation — Python data visualization. Large Language Models (LLMs) and AI Tools Prompt Engineering Guide — strategies for effective LLM use. LangChain documentation — framework for building applications powered by LLMs in Python. OpenAI API documentation — reference for integrating LLMs into data workflows. Recommended Books Advanced R by Hadley Wickham. R for Data Science by Grolemund &amp; Wickham. Fluent Python (2nd Edition) by Luciano Ramalho. Effective Python by Brett Slatkin. SQL for Data Scientists by Renee M. P. Teate. Miscellaneous Shiny — open-source R package for interactive apps. Streamlit — Python alternative for quick dashboards. Rcpp for Seamless R and C++ Integration — extend R with C++. Engineering Production-Grade Shiny Apps — best practices for robust Shiny development.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>